

# **Travis John**

# UX/UI Designer | Front-end Developer

Portfolio: https://travis-john.github.io



Contact

travis.wl.john@gmail.com +1 336 254 1943 github.com/travis-john codepen.io/travis\_john dribbble.com/travis\_john

#### **HELLO**

User Experience Designer with 3+ years of experience with skills front-end development. Providing strong problem-solving skills and a keen eye for intuitive and accessible interfaces. An excellent communicator and collaborator who works well in team-based projects and independently with very strong interpersonal skills. Effectively leveraging interest in solving complex problems by contributing as a part of a fast-paced, quality-driven team.

#### **Experience**



## **Experience Designer**

October 2019 to January 2021 Harte Hanks @ Cisco | Raleigh, NC

- Created high fidelity prototypes in Invision that are implemented on Cisco.com
- Defined and implemented new design system for Cisco CX emails
- Defined standardization requirements for all Digital Lifecycle Journeys team pages
- Participated in release deployments
- Participated in maintaining the React Cisco UI library
- Created and maintained visual assets
- A11Y enhancements and suggestions as needed



### **User Interface Designer**

May 2017 to October 2019 BB&T | Raleigh, NC

- Designed and optimized components for public sites
- Created and maintained visual assets
- Fixed functional and accessibility defects when discovered
- Maintained git repository with all code related to public sites



Project Lead - Preservation

July 2011 to June 2016

HF Group | Browns Summit, NC

- Served as representative for Federal Government Clients
- Maintained client standards
- Coordinated handling and scanning of antique publications
- Created high-resolution PDFs and preservation facsimiles  $% \left( 1\right) =\left( 1\right) \left( 1\right) \left$

# **CERTIFICATIONS**



Certified Professional in Accessibility Core Competencies
International Association of Accessibility Professionals

Dec 2018 - Dec 2021



Full Stack Development
University of North Carolina at Chapel Hill
April 2020

#### **EDUCATION**

M.A. Interactive Media

July 2016 to May 2017 Elon University | Elon, NC

**B.A Media Arts & Entertainment** 

August 2007 to May 2011 Elon University | Elon, NC

#### **NOTABLE PROJECTS**

Email Template Library

CISCO September 2020 to January 2021

A new design system for Cisco CX emails intentionally designed to not look like marketing emails. I was in charge of defining template layouts, visual elements, implementing design

system as requests were made, and building the master Sketch file for the system.

TRUIST H

media.truist.com

August 2019 to October 2019

The homepage and news aggregate page for Truist bank that would take the place of BBT and Suntrust bank's media pages. I designed the layout and UI elements based on then-current BBT components so as to speed up implementation using Adobe AEM.

BB&T

bbt.com

May 2017 to July 2019

I was part of the design team that designed and implemented the new bbt.com for launch in June 2017. My responsibility included defining the page layouts for the Small Business and Commercial sections of the site. Post-launch, I aided in the design and development of UI improvements and more targeted components to be implemented on the personal section of the site, namely the cash rewards calculator.

#### **PROFICIENCIES**

HTML & CSS

Javascript

React

Git

Node.js Sketch | Invision

Adobe Photoshop

**WCAG 2.0** 

Responsive Design

Microsoft Office

